

DATA SCIENTIST · ECONOMICS RESEARCHER

Av. de Valdemarin 91A 1°D, 28023, Madrid, Spain

□ (+34) 651 808 171 | work@pabloforero.eu | www.pabloforero.eu | pforero | pforero

Summary

Data Scientist at Allfunds' Innovation Lab. Strong analytical and technological skills. Specialist in modelling and predictive analysis. Stochastic models, time series, dynamic programming, machine learning and neural networks. Enthusiast of free open source software and modern industry practices.

Work Experience ____

Allfunds Madrid, Spain

DATA SCIENTIST, INNOVATION LAB

2018 - Present

- · Developed a predictive model using Random Forests, in order to profile retail costumers fund buying preferences.
- · Started an experimental project for classifying share classes using Natural Langugage Processing with prospectus in PDF format.
- Defined and analysed a project to implement a company wide CRM.
- Assisted in the development of a company Datalake
- Minerva
- · Daily email.
- · Eva.
- Arcus

SAIS John Hopkins University

Bologna, Italy

TEACHING ASSISTANT 201

• Teaching assistant in International Trade for Professor G. Plummer.

Banif (Santander Private Banking)

Madrid, Spain

ANALYST, ASSET MANAGEMENT

2009 - 2010

- · Support/Analysis.
- · Fixed Income.

Renaissance Capital

London, UK

INTERN, RESEARCH

2008

• Sub-saharan Emerging Markets.

CQS Hedge Fund

London, UK

INTERN, RESEARCH

2008

2007

· Pension Plans.

ING Capital

London, UK

Intern, Research

· Easter European Emerging Markets.

Education

European University Institute

Florence, Italy

Ph.D. (ABD) IN ECONOMICS

2012 - 2017

- Thesis title: Competition, Tasks and Earnings Inequality
- Supervisor: Ramon Marimón

European University Institute

Florence, Italy

MRES IN ECONOMICS

2013

Universidad de Navarra

MSC IN ECONOMICS AND FINANCE

Pamplona, Spain

University of Exeter

Exeter, UK

B.A. IN ECONOMICS AND POLITICS

2006 - 2009

Professional Activities

EABCN Training School Florence, Italy 2016

PARTICIPANT

• Micro-Structure of Trade - Theory and Evidence

• Taught by Klaus Adam

Workshop on Economic Policy Challenges Florence, Italy

2016

DISCUSSANT

• The Optimal Inflation Rate and Firm-Level Productivity Trends

• By Klaus Adam and Henning Weber

The Econometric Society 2016 European Winter Meeting Edinburgh, UK

PRESENTING 2016

Simposio de la Asociación Española de Economía Bilbao, Spain

PRESENTING 2016

Zurich Initiative on Computational Economics Zurich, Switzerland

PARTICIPANT

COEURE Workshop on Labour Markets Brussels, Belgium

• EU Dual Labour Markets: Consequences and Potential Reforms

Skills

Research International Trade, Macroeconomics, Labour Economics, Computational Economics

Languages Spanish, English, French (Basic), Italian (Basic)

Programming Languages Python, Matlab, SQL, LaTeX, Julia, VBA

> **Statistical Tools** Excel, Dynare, Eviews, Stata

> > **Cloud Tools** BigQuery, Google Storage, Composer Tools Docker, Sphinx, Git, Office, Airflow, PyTorch